It seems today ♪
That all you see ♪
Is violence in movies and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
On which we used to rely? ♪
Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man who
positively can do ♪
All the things that make us ♪
Laugh and cry ♪
He's... a... Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
Hi, I'm Peter Griffin.
It's almost Oscar night.
Boy, we've lost so many greats this year,
including a dead costume designer
who will get spill-over applause
from the photo of Sean Connery
that directly precedes him.
Tonight, we salute
some past Best Picture winners,
whichever ones I spin on this wheel.
The wheel has spoken!
The Silence of the Lambs.
♪ ♪
Ah... what a beautiful day
to not get bodily fluids
thrown in your face and hair.
And now, for some rock tunes
to pump me up.
One, two princes kneel before you... ♪
Oh, right, 'cause it's the early '90s.
Vaulting over a log.
Jumping a water hazard.
Climbing up a cargo net.
Becoming an FBI agent is basically
like being on Battle of the Network Stars.
- You rockets ain't in... ♪
-(music stops)
♪ ♪
- Aah!
- Agent Starling.
Good to see you.
Wh-Why is your face so big?
Oh, this movie
is mostly extreme close-ups.
Oh. Yeah. Weird.
Anyway, sorry you had to come so quickly,
but this thing with no timetable
couldn't wait.
We need you to talk
to a super smart psychopath.
How smart?
Like, he can do
the New York Times crossword
through Thursday.
Friday, he can maybe get a corner or two.
So, what's the job?
Fancy creep, eats people.
- Talk to him.
- Got it.
And this is a big deal,
'cause you're a woman.
We're not gonna say it's a big deal,
but everyone watching
will know it's a big deal
'cause of the time period,
even though a man is helping you.
Now run along, toots.
(bird cawing)
(yelling gibberish)
So, you're in the FBI, huh?
Me too.
Got this bad boy in Venice Beach.
Okay, all right.
You can talk to Lecter now.
♪ ♪
Hello, Clarice.
Dr. Lecter, I need your help.
Nope, nope, nope.
I'll only help if there's a quid pro quo.
(sighs) Okay, what is it?
I want Mario Lopez to record
my outgoing voice mail message.
What?! You're insane!
He's a huge star
at this specific sliver of time.
Figure it out. Those are my terms.
♪ ♪
(gasps)
Sorry, these Capri Suns
are notoriously difficult to open.
(Spin Doctors' "Two Princes"
playing on radio)
Yeah, one, two... ♪
(faintly): That's what I said now ♪
- Princes... ♪
-(music stops)
(straining)
You need some help?
Yeah, thanks.
I can't seem to get
this giant 1991 computer
into the back of my van.
Careful, I had it on
for 20 minutes, so it's very hot.
(grunts)
Okay, I got what you asked for.
MARIO LOPEZ: Hey, this is Mario Lopez
letting you know that Hannibal Lecter
can't get to the phone right now,
so please leave a message.
And now, I think
I'm about to be saved by the...
(beep)
Not good enough!
I wanted him to record it as Slater.
What?! You never said that.
It should've been understood.
Don't test me, Starling.
A census taker did that once,
and I ate his liver with dry Cheerios
and a mashed-up banana.
(slurping)
Sorry, I'm just a little nervous.
When I was a girl,
I went to live on my uncle's farm,
and I heard these lambs screaming,
screaming as they were being slaughtered.
It was horrible.
-(applause)
- And I want to thank
Alan Weiss at William Morris.
Also, my high school drama teacher,
Lucas Wohl.
-(orchestral music plays)
- Oh, they were just
killing those poor lambs.
I wanted to save them, but I couldn't.
And, Mandy and Jenny
at home, go to bed, kids.
Mommy did it!
I am coming home with one of these!
-(laughing)
-(applause)
♪ ♪
CVS brand lotion?
It's the same ingredients as Nivea.
It puts the off-brand lotion on its skin,
or else it gets the hose again.
The top isn't even a pump.
You're paying for the pump!
♪ ♪
Dr. Lecter, we are running out of time.
I need you to give me some clue,
anything that might
lead me in the right direction.
(sighs) His name's Buffalo Bill,
heavyset blond kid
who lives in that crappy place
behind McDonald's.
Hmm.
I'll have to really lean
on my budding criminology skills
to decipher these obscure breadcrumbs.
♪ ♪
(gasps slowly)
Coming up, dinner.
But first, I turn my back
to a dangerous murderer.
(regurgitates)
(indistinct chatter)
Oh, hey, Sarge.
Your wife called and said it was urgent.
Oh, uh, okay.
Yeah, she sounded very not happy.
You need to call her back ASAP.
Got it, thanks.
Starting to think I did this guy a favor.
It puts its finger on the doorbell.
We're looking for someone.
Have you seen her?
Oh, wait, is she that
great, big, huge, plump,
very large, Rubenesque,
fat girl who went missing?
Yes, she is rather heavy,
and as you can see,
not particularly attractive.
We've had reports that her personality
is quite grating as well.
MEG (distant): I can still hear you guys!
(panting)
(gasps)
I'm not loving this night vision setting.
Maybe I should
try Night at the Roxbury vision.
(Haddaway's "What Is Love?" playing)
♪ ♪
- You? Me? You?
- What is love? ♪
- Aah!
It puts the bullet in the fat guy.
And, for having successfully
scaled a cargo net
and connecting two note cards
with a piece of red string,
Clarice Starling,
you are now officially a lady FBI.
(applause)
(phone ringing)
You should probably answer that.
I mean, you're the closest thing
to a secretary in here.
Ugh.
Hello, FBI. This is Clarice speaking.
Hello, Clarice.
I just wanted to let you know
that I respect you,
and how important it is
that you're a woman.
Thank you for saying so, Doctor.
'Cause if you were a man,
I would definitely
be captured or dead by now.
- Oh, I...
- Like, if you're Clint Eastwood, I'm dead.
- Harrison Ford? Dead.
- Well, Doctor, I've really got...
You know, I'm not betting
against the Twin Peaks guy--
what's his name? Creepy white guy.
- Kyle MacLachlan.
- Kyle MacLachlan, right.
How do I keep forgetting that?
It's like in my top five dude names.
I have a list.
- Dr. Lecter, I really have to go.
- So do I.
♪ ♪
I'm having an old friend for dinner.
Y-You're gonna eat a friend?
That was kind of
supposed to be the last line,
and you ruined it.
I'm gonna say it again
and then hang up quickly.
(clears throat)
I'm having an old friend for dinner.
What?!
Oh, my God, this bitch.
♪ ♪
PETER: My name is...
whatever Kevin Spacey's name was
in this movie.
I bet you think behind that door is
a happy, all-American family.
Nope.
Just me in the shower
with Johnson & Johnson and Johnson.
There were some tears.
That's my wife out there, cutting roses.
Oh, just a heads-up,
there's a ton of roses in this.
I guess they're
supposed to mean something. (sighs)
You know, when I agreed to this,
I 100% thought it was American Pie.
Always read the second word of the title
before you sign something.
Oh, hi, Carolyn. We're your gay neighbors.
That's right, and we're
the only happy people
in the entire film.
PETER: Oh, that's the other thing.
This movie really wants you to know
that traditional families
are the messed-up ones.
If you don't want two hours of that,
go turn on The Matrix.
Aw, why aren't we doing that?
Have a great day,
two-dimensional '90s gay neighbors.
- Who are both named Jim.
- Right, who are both named Jim.
- Good morning, my darling.
- Hello, my love.
PETER: Keep in mind
that 9/11 hasn't happened yet.
So a strained family dynamic
is still the most dramatic thing there is.
Wow, what a beautiful,
fully heterosexual neighborhood.
Yeah, no. What's up is down here, bro.
Oh, hi, you must be our new neighbors.
I'm Carolyn Burnham,
RE/MAX's top crying realtor in the area.
Uh, thanks, but we just bought a house,
so we don't really need a realtor.
(crying)
- You don't?
- S-Sorry.
It's okay. You know what?
We'll buy another one.
Oh, great. Great.
Oh, looks like your son and my daughter
are getting to know each other.
Check out this video
I took of a plastic bag.
♪ ♪
I'm thinking about sending it in
to America's Funniest Home Videos.
Really? Do you think it's funny enough?
I don't know. I just want to spend $2,000
flying to Los Angeles to maybe win $1,000.
(crowd cheering inside)
-(whistle blows)
- ANNOUNCER: That's halftime.
And now, please welcome
the Suburbia High School
cheer quad, the Dockers Zipper Pushers.
(upbeat music plays)
♪ ♪
Who is that?
(sultry music plays)
♪ ♪
Aah! Aw, damn it. Aw, stop. Stop.
I have seasonal allergies, guys. (sneezes)
-(upbeat music resumes)
- ANNOUNCER: All right.
Now the marching band to play
the Suburbia High School fight song.
(playing "Two Princes" by Spin Doctors)
Geez, again with this song?
Shut up and kiss me, other gay Jim.
(both moaning)
Oh, no. No.
I'm very against that.
Remember that for later.
PETER: The next day, I quit my job
and was in no way run out of the industry
for groping a busboy in Nantucket.
It was a joke. I was razzing the guy.
Come on.
(sizzling)
I got a new job
at a fake movie fast food restaurant.
God, why are movies
so bad at naming restaurants?
Welcome to
Mr. Smiley's BurgerTownVilleLand.
Would you like to try a Large McIntyre?
LOIS: Yes, my lover and I
will each have adultery burgers.
Second window.
(moaning)
- Two adultery burgers.
-(gasps) Lester!
(chuckles nervously)
Listen, let's not make a big scene here.
We can talk about this when we get...
You don't get to tell me
what to do anymore.
We need more ketchup.
All right, there are some things
you can tell me to do.
After that, I started
lifting weights in my garage.
But I lost track of a spider
that crawled behind the heavy ones,
so I had to use the dainty weights
ladies walk with.
Oh, hey. You got those drugs?
Yep, right here.
Oh, my God.
Look at that plastic bag.
So beautiful.
Do you do a lot of the drugs yourself?
I do, yes.
Okay, let me just get on my knees
and roll a joint at crotch level
like all drug dealers do.
Great, and I'll just lean back,
away from the drugs
like all drug users do.
What the hell?
Am I seeing what I think I'm seeing?
Help me out here, Mr. Furley.
How did this thing win an Oscar?
It's basically Austin Powers.
♪ ♪
Yo, yo, check this out.
What if, like, Kramer is just
a figment of Jerry's imagination?
- Wow. Yeah.
-'Cause think about it.
We-we never see him
interacting with anyone else.
Yeah.
Well-well, wait.
I mean, w... Uh, we-we do.
Oh, boy, am I glad you're here.
I don't think I like what I saw earlier.
Oh, was it The Phantom Menace,
which also came out this same year?
Yeah, what a mess.
Ricky, go on home.
I need to talk to Lester.
Aw, I don't want to.
(singsongy): There's plastic bags.
(gasps) There are?
Hey, you know how
there's two things we know for sure?
We'll always be able
to bring box cutters on planes,
- and I'm heterosexual?
- Yeah, of course.
Well, turns out only
one of those things is true.
Mm...
Look, I think I gave you the wrong idea
with these pink weights
and pantomiming oral with your son.
- I'm straight.
- I'm so sorry!
I got to go start a megachurch!
Eh, seems right.
Oh, hey, what are you doing here?
I have a flight tomorrow,
and Jane said
I could borrow your box cutter.
Man, I love cutting boxes on planes.
And also-- and this is kind
of embarrassing and unearned--
but I think you're sexy,
and I want to have sex with you.
Ah, sweet! Let's do this.
I should let you know, I'm a virgin.
Not a deal-breaker.
And I should let you know
I'm Chris Hansen from To Catch a Predator.
Aw, crap. Somebody shoot me.
(gunshot)
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
Whoa, you're Chris Hansen!
Hey, what do you do
with all the leftover pedophile pizza?
PETER: Well, that was American Beauty.
See you at the Oscars.
I'll be there with my mom.
That's not a big,
obvious sign of something, right?
♪ ♪
- How's work, Ralph?
- It's a breeze.
(both laughing)
- Give my best to Judy.
- Will do.
Hi, my name's Forrest.
Forrest Gump.
Would it be okay
if I sugarcoat race relations
in the South for the next
two and a half hours?
Honey, I'm a Black woman
in a '90s Hollywood movie,
- that's what I'm here for.
- Great.
My mama always said life
was like a box of Good & Plenty:
most people just throw it away.
One day on the bus to school,
I met Jenny.
She was the love of my life.
Hey, look, it's a guy
with nonstandard legs.
Let's bully and throw
rocks at him and not me.
Run, Forrest, run!
PETER: And in a magical moment
whose explanation
I assume was cut for time,
I could suddenly run very fast.
But I happened to do it
in front of the meanest
lifeguard in Alabama.
- No running!
- It's for a movie. God.
-(cheering)
- I was such a fast runner,
I went on to play college movie football,
where all the tacklers
dive two feet behind you and miss.
After I graduated,
I joined the Army
and got shipped off to war.
Vietnam is where
I met my best friend, Bubba,
who really wanted
to have his own squid fishing boat.
In fact, he knew just about
everything you could do with a squid.
Well, there's calamari...
That's about it.
Ambush! (screaming)
Oh, my God, Lieutenant Dan!
Damn it, save yourself, Gump.
- Leave me here.
- All right.
(explosion)
Bubba was also shot.
And as always happens when a soldier dies,
we discussed business ideas.
I'm dying, Forrest.
I want you to buy
a squid boat in my honor.
How about a gym
exclusively for big white women?
- There could be machines that...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You had me at "big white women."
(exhales)
-(chanting)
- After I got home from Vietnam,
I got to speak at a generic protest.
There's only one thing
to say about Vietnam:
I had this awesome red stuff
on all my food.
I don't 'member what it's called.
It's not hot sauce, but it's not ketchup.
I think it's got a rooster on the label.
Forrest!
(gasps) Jenny!
Aah! Son of a bitch!
See, guys? This is why no running.
PETER: And then--
I know, it's still not over yet--
I bought a squid boat.
Lieutenant Dan was also working with me.
And you know who's super helpful on a boat
that's constantly rocking in the water?
A wheelchair guy.
Hey, Forrest, I got our lunches.
Aah!
So after I was rich,
Jenny came back
and had sex with me one time.
Wow, that was great.
Sorry I was naming presidents during.
So, we getting married or what?
You don't want to marry me, Forrest.
Yeah, you're right.
Okay, well, have a good night.
And then, shockingly late in the movie,
I started running again.
Like, across the country.
Several times.
The whole sequence
is a full eight minutes.
I mean, sometimes this whole movie
feels like it was written
by a seven-year-old
who just ate a bunch of candy.
But I checked, it's just a regular guy.
Anyway, at least we were finally
to the time in our nation's history
when I could listen to this.
Princes, princes who adore you. ♪
(knocking)
Forrest!
I brought you chocolates
picked over by strangers.
Forrest, I'm sick.
- Sick? With what?
-(whispers indistinctly)
Oh, I did a movie about that once.
It's called Splash.
No, Forrest. (whispers indistinctly)
Oh, I thought you said mermaids.
But I did a movie about your thing, too.
But that's not all.
I want you to meet my son.
Six hours in makeup. One line.
You're his father.
Father?
Is he... like me?
Uhp, you died.
And... feather!
♪ ♪
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH